people have always said ice cream isn't
good for weight loss and that is just
absolutely false in today's video I'll
be sharing three low calorie chocolate
ice cream recipes that use various
techniques and tricks to enhance quality
texture and taste so make sure you stick
around for the full video let's get into
it for this recipe all we need to do is
grab a pint and put it on a scale into
the Pint we will add 160 G 1% milk 200
80 g unsweetened almond milk and 2.1 g
vanilla extract I use high protein milk
since it has nearly double the protein
of regular milk but the same amount of
calories today I am using the HB brand
because it is slightly cheaper but fair
life works here as well since they
technically don't make 1% milk I just
use 80 g fat-free milk and 80 g 2% milk
to make my own put the Pint off to the
side and grab a small bowl into it add
50 g urethral or swerve you can use the
sweetener of your choice but this is
what I have found to give me the best
results so it is my go-to on top of the
urethra tal add 8 G cocoa powder 1 G
salt and 1 G zanan gum for these recipes
I would make sure you are using a
highquality cocoa powder I have been
using this blend from King Arthur for
over a year now and it is the best I
have ever had if you would be interested
in trying it out I will put a link in
the description below also don't skip
out on the zanan gum it helps make all
ice cream remarkably smoother and
creamier mix the dry ingredients
together and grab a small hand blender
or an immersion blender while mixing the
wet ingredients slowly pour in the dry
ingredients this usually takes me about
30 seconds once finished keep mixing for
an additional 90 seconds this will make
sure everything is dissolved and
dispersed evenly put a lid on your pint
and freeze it for 24 hours when you are
ready to eat grab your pint and rinse
the outside under hot water for 1 minute
dry the Pint off load it up and hit the
light ice cream function once the first
spin is done it looks like this it is
nearly done but not quite there yet even
though we don't have any mixins we will
use the mixin setting over the last
month I have been testing various
combinations for the best cream-like
texture and consistency and this is what
I have found to work the best if you
were looking for a soft serve cream
consistency I would use the respin
button for the Second Spin instead now
this ice cream is definitely good
especially for the calories but we can
make it much better with just a few
tweaks I didn't want to post this recipe
if was a simpler way to get something to
taste just as good with similar calories
Fairlife Chocolate Milk is a very
popular solo ingredient to use for
creamy ice cream so I had to make sure
mine was better first both of these were
spun at the same time for the same
amount but the fair life was still
crumbly so I sent it in for another rein
grab from the fair life the creamiest
part like the most ice cream looking
part very chocolatey nice and sweet I'll
put money that's
mine tastes like a water down version of
chocolate ice cream which I'm guessing
is milk all right this the first one
mine yeah yeah mine wins time to keep
testing we will start with a high-sided
container and into it add 440 G 1% milk
and 2.1 g vanilla extract the use of
strictly cow's milk will drastically
improve the texture and consistency of
our ice cream almond milk is made up of
about 98% water while milk comes in at
about 87% this as well as the
composition of proteins found in milk is
massively important to a better Cream
leading to a drastic difference in Ice
Crystal formation creating a better
mouth feel and smoother texture grab a
small bowl and into it add 50 g swerve 8
G cocoa powder 1 G salt and 1 G zanan
gum mix to combine you can use a small
hand blender here but I would recommend
using an immersion blender if you have
one
why the immersion blender just does a
much better job at mixing the
ingredients in and keeping them
suspended in the liquid while it freezes
look at this very recipe made the exact
same way the one made with the immersion
blender is darker aka the cocoa powder
didn't sink to the bottom making it
useless and it has a better final
consistency slowly pour in the dry
ingredients and once they are dissolved
continue mixing for another 90 seconds
pour the mixture into your pint pop the
top on label it so you don't get
confused with with your other creamy
recipes and freeze for 24 hours when
hunger strikes rinse off the outside of
the Pint load it into the creamy and run
it on the light ice cream setting load
the Pint right back up hit that mixing
button for pint consistency or push the
respin button for soft serve consistency
this cream is a couple notches better
than the first one but this last
chocolate cream is that top
milk that cream pure
vanilla
sweeteners that's a we are going to
start with a high-sided container on our
scale into it we will add 410 G 1% milk
an egg yolk and 2.1 GS vanilla extract
the egg yolk adds a tremendous boost in
taste and texture and in my last video I
even did a blind taste test to be 100%
positive if this isn't the egg one I
would be
shocked with egg telling you egg yolk
worth it 100% love it you can check out
that video after you watch this one for
more on that but if you don't want to
use an egg yolk you can just Sub in
another 15 G of milk add a small bowl to
your scale and add 50 g swerve 10 G
cocoa powder 1 G salt and 1 G zanan gum
mix the dry ingredients together grab
another small bowl and throw in 14 G of
semisweet chocolate I want this to be
the best chocolate ice cream possible so
I am using a higher quality baker's
chocolate but if you only have chocolate
chips that will work as well for this
recipe I would strongly recommend using
an immers blender start out by mixing
the wet ingredients together for 30
seconds we need to melt this chocolate
and add it to the wet ingredients but if
we add it when the wet ingredients are
cold most of the chocolate will just get
hard again which is pointless to
circumvent this issue we are going to
heat up our wet ingredients throw the
milk mixture in the microwave for 30 to
60 seconds or until it reaches 80 to 90°
F and mix it with a spoon this will be
warm enough to keep the chocolate melted
until we mix but cold enough to not have
the egg cook or milk curdle if you heat
it up for just 30 seconds too long you
can end up with chunks of milk and
cooked egg in your ice cream so I would
recommend microwaving in 30second
intervals and checking the temperature
until it reaches 80° as soon as the milk
mixture is ready heat the chocolate up
for 45 to 60 seconds or until melted and
mix it around to get an even consistency
pour the chocolate right into the milk
mixture getting every last bit of that
chocolate in there and then blend for 30
seconds once fully mixed in start slowly
adding the dry ingredients until
dissolved and continue mixing for 90
seconds your kitchen should now smell
like hot chocolate and it is time to
pour it into the Pint if you want to be
extra cautious of any pieces of hardened
chocolate or possible cooked egg you can
use a strainer as you pour personally I
have never had an issue but I don't want
the blame if chunks of chocolate break
your creamy please cream safely I would
wait about 10 minutes before you put the
top on and put it in the freezer I
actually do this with every ice cream I
make now because I never get that Frozen
lump in the middle of my pint anymore
that could break my creamy see I am also
creaming safely put the pint in the
freezer for 36 hours yes 36 hours even
with the 36-hour weight you could have
been eating this recipe 132 hours ago if
you had my cookbook these creams have
been in there for over a week and each
recipe is always uploaded to The
cookbook well before a video is made get
over 120 recipes by clicking the link in
the pin comment and use code E4 CM for
10% off the temperature of this liquid
is much much hotter than what would
typically go in the freezer so 36 hours
is a must after 24 hours I got frozen
yogurt the best frozen yogurt I have
ever had but if you want cream you will
need a weit I promise you it is worth it
plus you can just make four or five at
the same time so you never have to wait
again getting 15 pints was the best
decision I have ever made I will put
links in the description if you never
want to wait for ice cream again either
while helping to support the channel
after being the most patient human being
on Earth grab your pint rinse the
outside for 1 minute and mix it on the
light ice cream setting load it back in
for a mix in setting to get a perfect
hagendaz likee consistency and it's time
to load some up in a waffle cone and
enjoy every single lick this will by far
be the best chocolate ice cream you have
ever had in this calorie range and I
guarantee you will want another one soon
after so I suggest making two at the
same time whatever recipe you choose
will have a fraction of the calories of
regular chocolate ice cream while having
more volume to keep you full and and
include an efficacious dose of protein
the only problem is some flavor
combinations just don't go well with
chocolate and sometimes a more neutral
flavor is needed vanilla ice cream can
do just that and this video here
achieves the perfect balance of calories
and flavor in every recipe I highly
recommend you check it out until next
time deuces